Teachers Union of the City of New York Records 5015
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Teachers Union vs. Board of Education, Lederman et al, 1950-1953 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  Notes, memos, correspondence, cases, legal documents
- Television, night beat program, 1958 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  Transcript of t.v. show, news clippings, post cards, correspondence
- Television and Education, 1957-1961 (Box 88, Folder 7)
- Timone Resolution to Ban Teachers Union, 1949-1960 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  Article reprints, news clippings, periodicals, open form letters, telegrams, broadside, correspondence, resolutions, press releases and related material
- Timone Resolution, American Jewish League against Communism, Inc., 1949-1952 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  News clippings, news releases, correspondence, resolution, report
- Timone Resolution, Protests from clergymen and religious organizations, 1950 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  Telegram, correspondence, statements
- Timone Resolution, protests from faculty groups and individual teachers, 1950 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  Statements, correspondence, resolutions, post cards form letters, notes
- Timone Resolution, protests from labor organization, 1950 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  Telegram, correspondence, form letters, statement
- Timone Resolution, protest from parent groups and individual parents, 1950 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  Post card, correspondence, form letters, copy of wire, note
- Timone Resolution, remarks, Board of Education, 1950 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  Remarks (addresses), notes, list of speakers, statement
- Timone Resolution, the Teachers Retirement Board, 1951 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  Resolutions, statement, correspondence, form letter, brief, special
- Timone Resolution, re: the use of school buildings, 1947-1957 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  News clippings, telegrams, form letters, press releases, statements, resolutions, periodical, cases
- Timone Resolution, re: use of school buildings; action taken by faculties, parents, miscellaneous organizations, 1951-1952 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, notes, form letter
- Timone Resolution, re: use of school buildings, (American Civil Liberties Union), 1951-1952 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  News clippings, correspondence, form letter, pamphlet case, report, testimony
- Timone Resolution, re: use of school buildings, appeal before state Commissioner Edward Wilson, 1951-1952 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  Cases, form letter, correspondence, telegrams, newspaper
- Timone Resolution, re: use of school buildings, Board of Education brief and T.U. reply, 1951 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  Cases, press release
- Timone Resolution, re: use of school buildings, Brief, "Motion to Strike" scandalous, 1950-1951 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  Cases, organization and individuals who signed Schultz-Shevlin attack, press release
- Timone Resolution, re: use of school buildings, copies of resolution, 1951-1952 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  Resolution, press releases, memo, newspapers, form letters, report, fact sheet, statements
- Timone Resolution, re: use of school buildings, miscellaneous, 1951-1952 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  Notice, press releases, cases, resolutions, petition form letter, statements, telegram, newspaper, correspondence
- Timone Resolution, re: use of school buildings, 1951-1952 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  News clippings; Timone Resolution See: Board of Education See: Teachers Union File
- Tribute, Abraham Lederman, Rose Russell, Lucille Spence, 1960-1961 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, news clipping, telegrams, bulletin, biographical information
- President Harry Truman (letters sent to), 1947-1948 (Box 90, Folder 9)
- Unemployment Insurance, 1931-1935 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  Press releases, bulletin, resolution, report, correspondence, form letters; Union Membership Eligibility See: Academic Freedom, Committee Letters and Answers
- Union Teacher, 1935 (Box 90, Folder 11)
- United Federation of Teachers, 1962-1963 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  Brief, news clippings, bulletin, minutes, publication correspondence, form letter
- United Labor Action Committee, 1950-1952 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  Memo, minutes, survey, resolution, message, appeal, correspondence, form letters, statement
- United Parents Association, 1949-1962 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  News clippings, report, minutes, releases, correspondence, form letters, memo, bulletin; United Parents Association See: Parents Association, United
- United Progressive Group, 1933-1935 (Box 91, Folder 3a)
  Publications, form letter
- United Public Workers of America, 1951 (Box 91, Folder 4)
- United Public Workers (T.U.), CIO-UPW convention, 1948 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  Telegram, constitution, resolutions, correspondence, bulletin, form letter, reservation form
- United Public Workers (T.U.), CIO National Convention, 1948-1949 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  Telegram, memo, summary, resolutions, pamphlet, form letters, correspondence, credential
- United Public Workers (T.U.), Federal Department, 1948-1950 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  Form letters, correspondence, press releases
- United Public Workers (T.U.), International Executive Board, 1948-1949 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  Minutes, outline, statement, resolutions, form letters, correspondence
- United Public Workers (T.U.), National Teachers Division, 1947-1952 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  Press releases, statements, minutes, telegram, speech, suggestions, correspondence, form letters, memo
- United Public Workers (T.U.), UPW Trial before CIO, 1949-1950 (Box 91, Folder 10)
  Press releases, reports, resolution, correspondence, form letters, pamphlet
- U. S. Congress, 1947-1948 (Box 91, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, form letters, telegrams
- U.S. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Judiciary. Subcommittee on Internal Security, 1952-1953 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  Bulletins, press releases, leaflet, correspondence, report, form letters
- U.S. Congressional Probes, 1948-1949 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  News clippings, clipping from magazine
- U.S. Department of Education, 1948-1950 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, announcement, releases
- Urban League, 1955-1961 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  Publication, releases, reports, program, receipts, correspondence, form letters
- In re: Case of Samuel Wallach, 1952 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  Case; Washington, University of See: Academic Freedom Witchhunts See: Academic Freedom
- Teachers, 1920 (Box 93, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Lusk Law Material (Box 93, Folder 3)
- Report to the Union (Box 93, Folder 4)
- The Man Who Hated Children [use copy] (Box 93, Folder 5)
- Rhodes School Demonstration [use copy] (Box 93, Folder 6)
- Crime Against the Schools [use copy] (Box 93, Folder 7)
- Mike Wallace interview with Rose Russell - May 15, 1957 [cassette tape copies - box 94, 95] (Box 93, Folder 8)
- Crimes Against Schools, Reel 2, L. Pauley, 1958 (Box 93, Folder 9)
- The Man Who Hated Children -- H. Dale (Box 93, Folder 10)
- Demonstrations 1950s? [use video available] (Box 93, Folder 11)
- Crime Schools (Box 93, Folder 12)
- Rose Russell Interviewed by Mike Wallace, May 15, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 1)
- Rose Russell Interview by Mike Wallace, Nightbeat, May 15, 1957 [use copy] (Box 95, Folder 1)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 96)
- Video digitized from the collection. (Box 97)
- Text digitized from the collection. (Box 98)